<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<scene name="NibelheimMemories">



<h1>Nibelheim - Memories of a Nightmare</h1>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic">At Tifa's house, Cloud picks out the melody of FF7's main theme on her piano.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I've heard this melody somewhere before. Managed to play well...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I have the sheet music for that song.<br/>Huh? Wait a minute! There's something inside the music sheet.</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p class="indent">Tifa,</p>
<p class="indent">What's happened to our town? Was it all an illusion, or just a dream? No, it was neither. I remember trying to get people out of the flames, but not having the strength... Burning with anger, I went to the reactor to kill Sephiroth.</p>
<p class="indent">But he was nowhere to be found. Instead, I found you, collapsed inside. I felt saving you was far more important than going after Sephiroth. There were several others that were still alive inside, but I was only able to save you.</p>
<p class="indent">As I was coming out of the reactor, Shinra troops were just arriving. I recall a scientist named Hojo was in charge. He ordered the troops to gather up everyone still alive for the experiment. I didn't know what type of experiment he was talking about, but I wasn't about to let them have my dearest student.</p>
<p class="indent">Putting you on my back, I headed down the mountain to the village. I used the Cure spell on you many times.</p>
<p class="indent">And started to head to Midgar to look for a doctor for you. I don't like that city, but my Cure spells weren't helping.</p>
<p class="indent">I decided to go to Midgar to find a doctor I could trust. I'm worried about you, but I can't settle down in one place for very long? Have you recovered fully? Are you well?</p>
<p class="indent">I wonder how many years have passed since then? I just got into town again, but I can't believe it... The whole town is back to normal, except for the strange beings with the black clothes all around...</p>
<p class="indent">The town reeks of Shinra, but I won't go after them. You may think I'm running from them, but it's just that I don't want anything to do with Shinra anymore. Feels like time is running out.</p>
<p class="indent">I'm sure you'll find this letter. And this gift for you. It should come in handy. I can't even jump anymore. But I hope you continue to sharpen your skills and remember what I taught you.</p>
<p class="indent">To my most precious student,<br/>From Zangan</p><br/>
<div class="highlight"/><p>Received "Final Heaven"</p>
<p class="italic">Entering the basement library of the Shinra mansion triggers in Cloud a rush of memories...</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p class="italic">Cloud and Zack are floating in the Mako chambers in the mansion's basement. A man comes in to feed them.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Man</b><br/>Hey! This is your food.</p>
<p class="italic">When he opens Zack's chamber, Zack punches him and gets out. He helps Cloud out, retrieves his sword, and drags Cloud with him out of Nibelheim. Fade to black.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Zack</b><br/>Oh, here!!<br/>Put on this.<br/>It smells a little though don't complain.<br/>You look pretty good with that.<br/>Well......</p>
<p class="italic">The scene fades in; Zack and Cloud, now both wearing a SOLDIER uniforms, are riding in the back of an old truck.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Zack</b><br/>Yo! Old guy! We at Midgar yet?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Driver</b><br/>Shaddap! You're lucky I even gave you a ride!</p>
<p class="italic">Zack sits back down beside Cloud.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Zack</b><br/>What're you gonna do once we get to Midgar?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>.........</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Zack</b><br/>I know what I'm gonna do.<br/>I got a place I can crash for a while...<br/>No wait, the mother lives there, too...</p>
<p class="italic-inline-nopad">He scratches his head.</p>
<p class="block-inline-nopad">Guess that's out...</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>.........</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Zack</b><br/>Yep... gotta change my plans!<br/>Hmm......<br/>No matter what I do, I need some money first...<br/>...Hey, wanna start a business? But what could we do?<br/>Hey, Cloud.<br/>Think there's anything I'd be good at?<br/>Hey old guy!<br/>What do you think I'd be good at?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Driver</b><br/>What're you yappin' about? You're still young ain't ya?<br/>Young folks should try everything!<br/>You gotta pay your dues while you're young.<br/>Go out and look for what you really want.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Zack</b><br/>Try everything... That's easy for him to say...</p>
<p class="italic-inline-nopad">He does squats for a minute.</p>
<p class="block-inline-nopad">HEY!<br/>Of course!<br/>I got a lot of brains and skill that other guys don't!<br/>That settles it!<br/>I'm gonna become a mercenary!<br/>Yeah! Thanks pops!</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Driver</b><br/>Hey... didn't you even hear a word I said?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Zack</b><br/>Listen, I'm gonna become a mercenary and that's that.<br/>Boring stuff, dangerous stuff, anything for money.<br/>I'm gonna be rich!<br/>So, Cloud? What are YOU gonna do?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Driver</b><br/>No, wait... you got it all wrong.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>u... uhhh......</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Zack</b><br/>Just kidding... I won't leave you hanging like that.</p>
<p class="italic-inline-nopad">He sits down next to Cloud.</p>
<p class="block-inline-nopad">...We're friends, right?<br/>Mercenaries, Cloud. That's what you an' me are gonna be.<br/>Understand, Cloud?</p>
<p class="italic">Some time later, they come to a cliff, Zack dragging Cloud with him. Gunfire sounds from behind them, and Zack runs back to fight the soldiers. He can't fight them off and comes back, stopping by Cloud. The soldiers shoot him and he falls back. They shoot him again until he lies still, then turn to Cloud.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Shinra Soldier</b><br/>What do you want to do with him?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Ah... ughhhh......</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Commander</b><br/>...Forget it. Just leave him.</p>
<p class="italic">They walk off, leaving Cloud behind with Zack's body. It starts to rain. Cloud manages to crawl over to Zack. He takes up his sword and throws his arms up to the sky. Before him is the city of Midgar.</p>

</scene>
