<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<scene name="JunonExecution">



<h1>Junon - A Public Execution</h1>

<h4><a href="#dream">Tifa Dreaming</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#captive">Captive in Junon</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#execution">A Public Execution</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#weapon">Shinra Fights Weapon</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#escape">Tifa's Escape</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#crew">Not Enough Crew</a></h4>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic"><a name="dream"></a>The screen is pitch black. Cloud sits in the distance.</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Cloud...<br/>Cloud...</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud gets up and starts walking away. Tifa runs after him.</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Tifa</b><br/>......I didn't know what to do. I was always like that...</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p class="italic">Flashback to the Sector 7 train station, before the events of the game. Cloud is lying near the steps and the train man and a dog are nearby.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Station Man</b><br/>What's the matter?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>ohhh...</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Station Man</b><br/>......poor kid.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Ooouugh......</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa runs over.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Are you all right?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>oo... uh... agh</p>
<p class="italic-inline-nopad">Flash.</p>
<p class="block-inline-nopad">Uh... uh... Tifa...?<br/>Tifa...?</p>
<p class="italic-inline-nopad">He gets to his feet.</p>
<p class="block-inline-nopad">Tifa!</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...............?<br/>Oh, Cloud!</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>That's right. I'm Cloud.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Is it really you, Cloud? I never thought I'd find you here!</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Yeah, it's been a while.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>What happened to you? You don't look well.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>......Yeah? It's nothing. I'm okay.</p>
<p class="italic">She turns away and he clutches his head for a moment. She turns back.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>How long has it been?</p>
<p class="italic">Flash.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Five years.</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>............</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What is it?</p>
<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...it's really been a long time.</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Actually, it's been seven years.<br/>You got your wish and joined SOLDIER, quit after the Sephiroth incident, and now you're a mercenary...<br/>You told me a lot about what happened after you left Nibelheim...<br/>But...<br/>...Something's wrong. I felt there was something strange about the things you talked about.<br/>All the things you didn't know that you should, And other things you shouldn't know that you did...<br/>I wanted to make sure...<br/>But then I heard... you were going far away...<br/>And I didn't want that...<br/>...I didn't know what to do. So, I thought I needed more time.<br/>And that's why I told you about the AVALANCHE job. I wanted to be with you, watch you.</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="captive"></a>Tifa wakes in Junon base to bright lights overhead.</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...ding......</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Barret</b><br/>Huh?</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Tifa</b><br/>The glare...</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Barret</b><br/>You'll be better soon. You've been asleep for a long time.</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I'm...... hungry....</p>
<p class="indent-grey"><b>Barret</b><br/>Hey, why don't you ask?</p>
<p class="block-inline">About him.</p>
<p class="italic">The glare fades and Tifa sits up.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...Because I'm scared.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Don't worry. I don't know what happened to Cloud either.<br/>Guess I shouldn't tell you not to worry...<br/>None of them know if he's all right either.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>He's still... alive, right?</p>
<p class="italic">Barret nods.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>How long... was I asleep?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Lessee now...... Must've been about 7 days.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>What about Sephiroth?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>You ain't over it yet. Remember that huge light, in the Northern Cave?<br/>Since then, the crater's been surrounded by a huge barrier of light.<br/>Everyone knows Sephiroth sleeps in that big hole, protected by the barrier.<br/>We can't do a damn thing about it. We just gotta wait till he wakes up.<br/>An' on topa that, some huge monster called Weapon's been on a rampage.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...Weapon?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Remember that huge monster that was with Sephiroth, at the bottom of the crater?<br/>Well it's up here now. They say it's some legendary monster from the past.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Weapon... is protecting Sephiroth?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Dunno. But he's up here goin' around tearin' shit up.<br/>Right now Rufus' fightin' it. I hate to say it, but he's got guts.<br/>We shoulda been the ones to destroy it, but we ain't got no time...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Time...<br/>...Hey! How about Meteor?</p>
<p class="italic">Barret opens the blinds to a large window as Tifa walks to look outside. Meteor hangs there in the sky.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Do we have to give up?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>...Dunno.</p>
<p class="italic">The door opens and Rufus enters.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>I thought Cloud would show up to save you all...<br/>Professor Hojo wanted to check up on Cloud, too.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>What are you going to do to Cloud?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>Sephiroth's alter ego...<br/>Meteor has been summoned... Essentially, it's all but over now.<br/>So, there's no need for you now.<br/>No, maybe there is an important task for you...</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="execution"></a>Heidegger enters.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>President! Preparations for the public execution are complete.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Execution!?<br/>What're ya gonna get by executin' us?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>You are to be executed for causing this situation.<br/>People are ignorant. They'll feel better as long as someone is punished.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>I take back what little praise I had for this damn jackass!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>Well, enjoy your last moments together.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He walks out.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>I'll tie your arms now.</p>
<p class="italic">Barret and Tifa are escorted down to the press room, where Scarlet waits with the media.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Is everyone here? These are the ones who brought this madness into the world!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>The hell are these people?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>We will be broadcasting your miserable deaths live on national television.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Large Man</b><br/>Scarlet, why a public execution in this day and age?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>With the chaos resulting from the Meteor reports, we desperately need to rally public support... it's better that we punish somebody, anybody.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>You make me sick...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>ha, ha, ha, ha!<br/>They'll never admit it, but everyone loves this stuff!<br/>We'll start with this girl.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>If you've gotta do it... do me first!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Camera, this way! Make sure you get this, the audience just eats up tearful goodbyes!</p>
<p class="italic">A soldier brings Tifa into the gas chamber, and Scarlet pushes her towards the chair.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>What are you doing!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>This is my special gas chamber. Take your time, and enjoy a slow painful death.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">She shoves Tifa into the chair.</p>
<p class="block-inline">Stuck up ^%$#&amp;!!</p>
<p class="italic-inline">She slaps Tifa.</p>
<p class="italic">Scarlet and the soldier walk out, the soldier dropping a key on the way.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Well now, the show's about to begin. Ha, ha, ha!</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>Emergency! Emergency!<br/>Weapon's approaching! Attention all military personnel: take your positions!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Press Representatives</b><br/>Oh no! It's Weapon!<br/>Run!</p>
<p class="italic">They all flee the press room except for the large man.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Hey, hey, all of you!<br/>Damn! Why now?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Large Man</b><br/>How does it feel now, Scarlet?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Hmm, so you didn't run? I'm impressed. How do I feel? Right now......<br/>Nngaaaaaahhhh!</p>
<p class="italic-inline">She collapses.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Huh!? Sleeping gas?</p>
<p class="italic">The large man reveals himself to be Cait Sith in disguise.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>Weirdo!!</p>
<p class="italic">Cait Sith and Barret dispatch the soldiers.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b> (untying Barret's arms)<br/>I'm here to help!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Why you......? Ain't you part of Shinra?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Let's just say I'm against capital punishment. Besides... I hate this broad. Come on, we gotta help Tifa.<br/>I'll keep watch at the entrance.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>......Fools...... I've already pushed... the switch...</p>
<p class="italic">Barret tugs at the door to the gas chamber.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>It won't open!</p>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic"><a name="weapon"></a>Meanwhile, in the command room, Rufus and Heidegger stand before a broad window overlooking the ocean.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>It's Weapon.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>There's been so many attacks lately. Can we handle it?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>I believe so. Your orders?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>No need to ask.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>We'll give it a shot from our big cannon.<br/>Open cannon doors!! Activate cannon. Target: Weapon!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Sailor</b><br/>Preparations complete!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>The cannon...<br/>Fire----!!!</p>
<p class="italic">The cannon fires a shot across the water. A moment of silence descends.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>Did we get 'em?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>Seems so...</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>Weapon approaching!<br/>Speed, 50 Knots!<br/>It's heading right toward us!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>It can't be! We hit it dead on!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>How about the cannon?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>It'll take time to reload.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>Then use regular fire power in the mean time!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>Yes sir! Open all artillery doors! Target: Weapon! Don't let it land!</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>Speed, 70 Knots!<br/>Weapon, closing in!!<br/>Not good! It's attacking!</p>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic">Back at the gas chamber, the gas turns on and Tifa starts squirming.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Gas!!<br/>Barret, help!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Hold your breath! Hold on as long as you can!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Come on! I can't hold on forever!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Shi-!<br/>The Gas Room's probably locked from a different room!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Hmm, we gotta go with a different plan. Let's get out of this room first.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Tifa! I'll help you, I promise!</p>
<p class="italic">They leave the press room, and the door locks behind them.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>No! They locked this too!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b> (from inside)<br/>Fools. Now, you can't save the girl.<br/>Ha, ha, ha, ha!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Goddammit......!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>OK, OK time for Plan B. Let's run to the airport!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Why the airport? An' leave Tifa there?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Trust me, trust me. We gotta take a chance.</p>
<p class="italic">If Barret goes the wrong way...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Where you goin'? The airport's the other way.</p>
<p class="italic">They run outside and run across Yuffie dressed as a reporter.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>I know you're in a hurry! But, please if I could have a word......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Shu'up!! I'm in a hurry!</p>
<p class="block-grey">Kiiiiin...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>Don't make so much noise...... It's me, ME! Yuffie!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>The hell you doin' here!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>I'll explain later! Now we gotta get to the airport!</p>
<p class="italic">They arrive at the airport.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Yo! You sure this is the right way? It's a dead end!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Uh oh? Did I make a wrong turn?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>You damn cat......! What the hell're we gonna do now? They all be comin' soon!<br/>Yo, better watch my back till the end... partner!</p>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic"><a name="escape"></a>Back in the gas chamber, Tifa manages to grab the dropped key with her feet and free herself from the chair.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Which button stops the gas...?</p>
<p class="italic-inline">She turns off the gas and then tries to tug open the door.</p>
<p class="block-inline">Open it---......</p>
<p class="italic">There is an explosion as Weapon blasts a hole in the ceiling above her.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>What d'you do? Hey! Open it!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>First you lock me in this weird place, and now you're telling me to come out? Make up your mind!</p>
<p class="italic">She climbs out the opening, down the outside of the base, and runs out across the cannon. Scarlet follows and they face off near the end of the cannon.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Our little game of hide and seek ends here.<br/>The execution may have been unsuccessful, but your death by falling from here and crashing into the water below still might be pretty exciting.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">Slap.</p>
<p class="block-inline">Stuck up to the end!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Quit slapping me! You old wench!!!</p>
<p class="italic">A slapping fight ensues, and Scarlet falls to her knees.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>God! I can't stand it!<br/>Take her away.<br/>Now it's time to pay up. I'll really drop you if you don't settle down!<br/>Ha, ha, ha, ha!</p>
<p class="block-grey">Run...<br/>Run to the end of the Cannon!!</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa runs to the end of the cannon as the airship, the Highwind, comes up from below and hovers nearby. Barret is out on deck, and he throws Tifa a rope. She jumps from the cannon and catches the rope as the Highwind flies away from Junon.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>You okay?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>My cheeks hurt a bid.<br/>Forget about that, what's all this about?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Well, I'll catch the details later.<br/>In any case, the Airship, Highwind, is now yours.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b> (lying on deck)<br/>Ha! Ha! ......urk!<br/>Well...... I'm glad you're safe.<br/>I'm going to stay up here a little longer.<br/>......Urk! ......I can't ride ships either in the air or water.</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa goes inside.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Crew Member</b><br/>My hands are full, so I'll excuse myself here!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>- Fly Airship<br/>- Chew the fat</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Fly Airship</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Crew Member</b><br/>So things have come to this... When you want to take off, just tell the pilot on the bridge.</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Chew the fat</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Crew Member</b><br/>......Well......... Um, what should I talk about?<br/>Wanna hear why we rebelled?<br/>Working on the Highwind, we spent every day slaving under Heidegger.<br/>Whenever he got yelled at by the President, he'd immediately take it out on the crew.<br/>We put up with this all the time. Even when he beat us.<br/>I mean, I finally made it on the crew of the famous Highwind, and there's no way I was going to quit over him.<br/>Let's see, it must've been a week ago... it was my shift and we were heading towards the North Cave.<br/>Everyone, including the President and Scarlet, got on.<br/>And with them, I saw Cid, a legendary pilot!<br/>And he was looking around the inside of the ship looking really, y'know, nostalgic......<br/>He even talked to us.<br/>I couldn't believe it! I was so impressed! He was every bit as warmhearted as we'd always heard.<br/>Cid said that if he had the Highwind, things would be a lot easier.<br/>And now here we are off to save the planet. It's true. He really overwhelmed me.<br/>And that's why we decided to help.<br/>After the North Cave, we went to Junon, and I started screaming 'Fire! Fire!'<br/>In the middle of all the commotion, we stole this ship from the Shinra.<br/>That's how it happened. .......Just a minor mutiny against our leaders.<br/>But Barret and you were captured by Heidegger......<br/>We waited seven days for a chance to rescue you guys, before we finally could.<br/>So thanks to our successful mission, we were able to see you again.<br/>I hope I didn't bore you too much with that long story.</p>

<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Dammit! Why didn't ya tell me you could fly an airship!?<br/>I thought...... Tifa was gone for good.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Sorry, but I had to do something to trick the enemy.<br/>Come on! Everyone is waiting!</p>
<p class="indent"><a name="crew"></a><b>Tifa</b><br/>Everyone? Everyone's here?</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa runs to the bridge.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Welcome to my airship--the Highwind!</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa looks around.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>What's wrong!? You should be more excited than that!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>Cid......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Yeah......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Not enough crew.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>What's that sad face for?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Well, it takes all kinds.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>Do you think we aren't strong enough without Cloud?<br/>Do you think we can't save the Planet alone?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Meteor is coming, and Weapon is on the rampage......<br/>At a time like this, I don't know what I'm supposed to do......<br/>No idea at all......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Get a hold of yourself Tifa! C'mon, let's think about this!<br/>No way we can get offa this train we're on!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>......If only Cloud was here, everything would be fine.<br/>Cloud would......<br/>Stand that cocky little way he did, and tell us what to do.<br/>He'd say, 'Everything's under control, Tifa.'</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Tifa! When'd you become such a wimp!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I'm sorry Barret.<br/>I'm kind of shocked myself. I'm so depressed.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>And Tifa...... the reason why we all thought it was Cloud was because......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>......I know.<br/>That's why I want to make sure. That's why I have to see him again.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>Cheer up, Tifa......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>......So glad you're all right Tifa.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>What? Does Cloud always gotta be around?.......<br/>We did fine without him in the beginning......<br/>Right? An' what happened to tough girl I used to know? Where'd she go to?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Tifa, I'll give you information Shinra.<br/>Ask me if there's anything you don't understand.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Crew Member 2</b><br/>Whenever anyone talks to me, I get all nervous and mess things up!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Hey you! What the hell are you doin'!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Crew Member 3</b><br/>All we have to do is just pilot. They don't have to talk to us.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>I want you to know that I didn't dislike him.<br/>Gotta admit he was a strange dude.<br/>Just when you thought he was cool, he'd go and do some damn fool thing.<br/>And when you thought he was smart, he'd show how stupid he was.<br/>Everything about him from his movements to his speech were kinda odd.<br/>Knowin' what I do now, I can see why he was that way.<br/>Well, as long as you stay alive, you just might see him again someday, so cheer up, sis.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>......I'll be able to see him someday.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>If we can find out where he is, the Highwind'll get us there in no time.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>......Maybe<br/>Cloud is still stuck deep in the North Crater, where the ground cracked and swallowed him up......<br/>Buried in the depths of the underground......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Deep within the earth...... are you talking about the Lifestream?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>The Lifestream sometimes gushes out the the surface from cracks in the ocean floor.<br/>I've heard that such a place exists.<br/>Maybe, just maybe Cloud's......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Pilot in Training (LV3)</b><br/>Waaaaah! Captain Cid!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Tifa, sorry, but I've gotta show this moron how to land the ship.<br/>Don't worry, it'll be done in a minute.<br/>Oh, and Tifa......<br/>No matter what your goal is, you've got to be prepared.<br/>Go to your room and get ready for our operation.<br/>I put a lot of things for the operation in your room, so put them in order.</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa goes to the Operations Room.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Crew Member 4</b><br/>Tifa, thank you for a job well done!</p>
<p class="italic">Back on the bridge...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Whenever I think of Cloud, everything gets all jumbled up.<br/>No matter how powerful Shinra or Hojo is, I can't believe they can create humans.<br/>But because of them, we know that Meteor is heading towards us......<br/>Y'know, even if I saw him, I don't have a damn idea what I'd do......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>There appears to be a small island near the Lifestream......<br/>They said the Lifestream sometimes suddenly gushes out at the south island.<br/>I remember hearing about this from Seto when I was a child, but I don't remember much else......<br/>I'm sorry...... Tifa.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Everything appears calm right now at Shinra.<br/>So now's the time to look for Cloud.<br/>I'm worried about him, too.<br/>I wonder where Cloud is. Or could he already be......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>Too much hope is the opposite of despair.<br/>An overpowering love may consume you in the end......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>OK! You just signal when you're ready to fly full speed.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Pilot in Training (LV4)</b><br/>Eaggggh! Are we going?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>- We're going<br/>- We're staying put</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Pilot in Training (LV4)</b><br/>Eagggggh! We're off!</p>

</scene>
