<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<scene name="Junon3">



<h1>Junon - Huge Materia</h1>

<h4><a href="#lower">Lower Junon</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#reactor">The Underwater Reactor</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#submarine">Stealing a Submarine</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#junon">Back in Junon</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#gelnika">Gelnika</a></h4>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic"><a name="lower"></a>Cloud and the others arrive at lower Junon.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Woman</b><br/>They say Shinra's gathering Huge Materia from around the world and bringing it to Junon.<br/>Bringing it to Junon must mean they want to use their airplanes.<br/>I've noticed there's been a lot of Shinra ships recently. I think they're going to the off-shore Underwater Reactor.<br/>Isn't Shinra trying to transport the Reactor's Huge Materia?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Older Man</b><br/>I remember years ago, seein' the Shinra build a long pipe underwater.<br/>The underwater reactor is connected to Junon by a pipe.<br/>You should be able to get to the reactor through it.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Priscilla</b><br/>Who are you---?<br/>Cloud!!<br/>Stupid jerk! Look how much you made me worry!! Were you at the Lifestream?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Yeah, that's right.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Priscilla</b><br/>You've gotta be more careful! Because you're going to marry me one day.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier by Elevator</b><br/>If you want to get on the elevator that badly, give me 10 gil!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Okay, I guess</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier by Elevator</b><br/>Hurry up and get in!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud takes the elevator to Upper Junon.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier on the Path to the Airport</b><br/>The Shinra's collecting Huge Materia at the Junon Undersea Reactor!<br/>When they're done, they'll bring it to this airport.<br/>Get out of here before you get in the way!<br/>What... me? I'm gonna be watching from here, so that I don't get in their way either!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud runs outside to the airport.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier</b><br/>After they get it, they'll take it to the airport and will transport it to Rocket Town by Gelnika. Don't let your guard down!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier 2</b><br/>They've finally started collecting the Huge Materia from the Junon Underwater Reactor.</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud leaves the base and starts down the street, then stops and turns to his companions.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I may be mistaken, but...... Doesn't it feel like we're missing something?</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="reactor"></a>Cloud and the others continue on. On the way to the reactor, they come across a commander drilling his soldiers.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Commander</b><br/>All right!! Let's see how hard you trained!<br/>Attention! Charge--!!</p>
<p class="italic">The soldiers all charge in the opposite direction.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Commander</b><br/>He... hey--!! That's the Underwater Reactor!! Come back!!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud gets on the first elevator with two soldiers and a redhead.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier</b><br/>How 'bout, whoever stays alive, gets to take her out?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier 2</b><br/>All right, you're on!!<br/>But... What if both of us...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier</b><br/>Whoa!! Don't even talk about that!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud defeats both of them.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Redhead</b><br/>...gulp... (Great... there went two perfectly good men!)</p>
<p class="italic">The elevator reaches the lower floor.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier 3</b><br/>OK! Back to work!! Back to work!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier 4</b><br/>Yawn... I'm sleepy!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier 3</b><br/>For Junon!!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others continue on down another elevator and through the underwater pipe to the reactor.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers in Reactor</b><br/>You, you're Cloud!!<br/>You are NOT getting this Huge Materia!!<br/>So you WERE after the Huge Materia!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others reach where the Huge Materia is stored.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>!? The Huge Materia!</p>
<p class="italic">They watch as a machine arm reaches down and pulls out the materia.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>Hey! A Crane Game!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Damn, just missed it!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>We were a little late...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>That's what you think! ^%$@#&amp;$#!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>They're gonna take it on that submarine!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>If we take a short cut, we might just make it......!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>There's the submarine dock just ahead of us.</p>
<p class="italic">They run to the submarine docks. Reno is standing with his back to them, supervising.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Did we make it!?</p>
<p class="italic">He watches as the Huge Materia is lowered into the red submarine.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reno</b><br/>What are you doing? Help load.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He turns around.</p>
<p class="block-inline">Cloud!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>Help?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>We're gonna help transport the Huge Materia... Reno!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>I'm SURE! You want me to do manual labor?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>You know I don't work for cheap!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>I refuse...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Looks like we barely made it.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Either give it to us or else.<br/>...which is it gonna be?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reno</b><br/>Unfortunately, I don't have time to deal with you.<br/>My priority is the Huge Materia!</p>
<p class="italic">He runs off, leaving Cloud and the others to fight a robot. After the battle, they find the red sub has already left.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Damn! The submarine!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>!? The Huge Materia!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Damn! So they was just buyin' time!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>We have to go after it!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>But it's already in the water!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>It left the dock!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>There is one way...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Hold on to your horses! Let's get it from them!!</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="submarine"></a>They run for the other submarine, and the soldiers on board turn frantic.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>Y, you...!<br/>You're not taking over this ship!</p>
<p class="italic">They defeat the soldiers and get on board.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>You want the Sub? Just try an' take it!<br/>Um... sir! Maybe we shouldn't piss them off...</p>
<p class="italic">They fight off these soldiers, too.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Come on, Cloud! Follow me!<br/>Damn, man!! ......what the...?<br/>Hey yo! Remember I was the leader first, man!<br/>Yo! We come a long ways since we got on that train!<br/>Lotsa things changed! This and that.</p>
<p class="italic">They enter the bridge.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Commander</b><br/>NO, NO!! This is terrible!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>We don't have much time left! I don't want to die!<br/>There's still so much more I've got to do!<br/>I never even got to do my special victory dance in battle!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Commander</b><br/>All right!! Then make this your first victory!!<br/>Go on, show 'em!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>Yes, sir!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Commander</b><br/>Remember your last training. Begin!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>Yes, sir!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Commander</b><br/>I'm back! An' now I got no regrets!!<br/>ATT----ACK!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Hmmmm...<br/>- Fight them<br/>- Take them prisoner</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Fight them</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Captain</b><br/>Let me show you how it's done.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Soldier</b><br/>Eyaaarrrgh!<br/>Captain... I can't hold on any longer!<br/>Eyaaarrrgh!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Captain</b><br/>Uggh... They got me.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Soldier 2</b><br/>The Special Pose...</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Take them prisoner</span></p>
  <p class="italic">The soldiers move aside to let Cloud and the others into the control room.</p>

<p class="italic">Cloud crouches down, wringing his hands. Yuffie doesn't look any better off.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Someone... please. I'm sorry I can't take it anymore.<br/>The lack of space, the shaking, the roar of the engine...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Stop your blubberin'!! How we gonna move this without you?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>I... I can't... I'm history.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>I can't fit in this seat... No good!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>Better hurry. Reno's getting away.</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa, Nanaki, or Cid goes up to the control panel and presses a button.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>See!?<br/>Just fiddle with the controls, and we'll get somewhere!<br/>Hey Cloud? Why don't you try piloting it?<br/>They say you don't get motion sickness if you're driving.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>It moved!<br/>Cloud!! Try it!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Hunka junk... just gotta do this!<br/>SEE! Now you take over!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud gets up.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Hey, you're right... I DO feel a little better driving.<br/>No sweat. Just leave everything to me.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Don't worry!<br/>If it breaks down, I'll smack it one--that'll fix it!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>You can do it, Cloud!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>I'll hold my breath, so HURRY!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Oh please drive safely, Cloud!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>Shinra's technology is really something.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>I'll be watchin' from here!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>I thank you! I am happy to be a hostage!<br/>Piloting a submarine is very difficult! I am completely clueless!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Commander</b><br/>Hey! Who am I to know!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Well, now what?<br/>- Read the manual<br/>- Sit in the seat<br/>- Leave it alone</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Read the manual</span></p>
  <p class="block-inline-nopad"><b>Submarine Operation Manual - Beginner's Edition</b></p>
  <p class="italic">[Controls reference]</p>
  <p class="block-inline-nopad">Mission Orders: Presently on the ocean floor near Junon, a Red Leader Submarine carrying Huge Materia is being escorted by covert Shinra Submarine Units.<br/>Furthermore, it has been confirmed that several mines have been dispersed onto the ocean floor.<br/>The ocean floor can only be monitored with Shinra's Sonar Radar Screen.<br/>Enemy subs can only be detected with the Sonar area. Get in front of the detected enemy sub and "Lock On"!!<br/>Push [] button to fire the torpedo!<br/>The mines are found on the radar screen at the top of the indicators. The mines inflict great damage, so be careful!<br/>Objective: Sink the Red Leader Submarine carrying the Huge Materia! Time Limit: 10 minutes!</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Sit in the seat</span></p>
  <p class="italic">Cloud sits down.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Everything seems set...<br/>- Start the mission!<br/>This switch...?<br/>Main screen: ON<br/>Change the screen mode.</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p>Leave it alone</p>
  <p class="italic">Cloud shrugs.</p>

<p class="italic">Cloud and the others get on with the mission and shoot down the red leader sub.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Phew--! We did it!!<br/>The Huge Materia should be at the bottom of the sea by now. Let's continue the search...</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>...All Shinra Submarine Units, do you read...?<br/>...All Shinra Submarine Units, do you read...?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Hmm...? ...Must be from Shinra.</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>...Report, No. 2...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Is it us?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>Oh my gawd...! They mean us.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>We need to respond!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>We've no choice but to respond.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>All right, I'll do it.<br/>This is Shinra No. 2... Everything's normal.</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>...Roger...<br/>...Your next mission is...<br/>...Return to Junon Dock...<br/>...We will transport the Huge Materia from the airport...<br/>...Those without other assignments will report for guard duty...<br/>That is all. Over and out...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Junon Airport... We should make it if we hurry.<br/>Forget about the Huge Materia for now.<br/>We're climbing!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Aye, aye... CAPTAIN!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>Take o-ff!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>The airport? No sweat!</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="junon"></a>They return to the surface and dock the submarine outside Junon. They hurry back to Junon.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Fisherman</b><br/>It seems like there's something going on again up there.<br/>Is that huge plane going to take off again with that deafening roar?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Older Man</b><br/>I just saw some Shinra soldiers all huddled together discussing something.<br/>They said a plane carrying Huge Materia would be taking off from the airport above.</p>
<p class="italic">They take the elevator to Upper Junon.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier on the Path to the Airport</b><br/>Finished loading the Huge Materia!<br/>All we have to do now is to ready the cargo ship, 'Gelnika', for departure and we're done!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud arrives at the airport only to watch Gelnika take off from Junon.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Oh no! The Huge Materia...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Let's go after it!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>Let's get there before they do and catch 'em!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>How 'bout us getting there beforehand and stealing it back?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>Let's go after it.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Where are they headed?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>Where's their destination?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Where's that thing headed?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Rocket Town, of course.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier</b><br/>Whew... I hope everything goes all right until we get to Rocket Town. Then, our mission is nearly complete.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier 2</b><br/>Not so fast. We still have one major task... we still have to transport the stuff...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier</b><br/>The stuff...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldier on the Path to the Airport</b><br/>I'm glad we got Gelnika to the Rocket Town safely.<br/>But they sure think big. Looks like they're going to use the Huge Materia's to break up Meteor...</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others leave Junon.</p>
<p class="italic">Searching the ocean floor, they find the red submarine.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>So this is the Leader Sub...<br/>Damn...... makes me sick just thinking about it...</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>...Huge Materia recovered...<br/>...no damage appears to have been sustained...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Phew... That's good to hear.</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>Received Key Item "Huge Materia"!</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="gelnika"></a>They also come across the sunken ship Gelnika.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>This is the Shinra's Gelnika type airplane... I wonder why it went down here?</p>
<p class="italic">They enter a side room.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What is this place...? Must be some kind of a Research Establishment because there's a Mako generator?</p>
<p class="italic">In the hallway, they encounter the Turks.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Turks!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rude</b><br/>...again?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reno</b><br/>We just seem to keep running into each other lately!<br/>There were weapons and Materia developed solely to destroy Sephiroth.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rude</b><br/>...but, it was attacked by Weapon and sunk to the bottom of the sea.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reno</b><br/>I can't give you what's here. We'll take out Sephiroth.<br/>I guess this is our last meeting.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rude</b><br/>I won't let you get in our way.</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others fight the Turks.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reno</b><br/>These guys are pretty tough.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He runs off.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rude</b><br/>..................</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He runs off after Reno.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>So Shinra's new, secret weapon was on this Airship...</p>
<p class="italic">Into the room beyond...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>This must be the Cargo Room...<br/>This is terrible... It's all messed up...</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others salvage what they can from the Cargo Room and leave for Rocket Town.</p>

</scene>
