<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<scene name="CityOfTheAncientsAerith">



<h1>City of the Ancients - Aerith's Prayer</h1>

<h4><a href="#arrival">Arrival at the City</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#key">Finding the Key</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#shinra">Meanwhile at Shinra HQ</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#highwind">Back on the Highwind</a></h4>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic"><a name="arrival"></a>Cloud and the others take Bugenhagen into the City of the Ancients and to one of the chambers.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Are you getting something?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Yes...... exactly...<br/>...give me a moment.</p>
<p class="italic">Bugenhagen floats up to the structure in the center of the room. Cloud joins him.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>The knowledge of the Ancients swirling around here is telling me one thing.<br/>The planet's in a crisis...<br/>A crisis beyond human power or endless time.<br/>It says, when the time comes, we must search for 'Holy'.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Holy?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Holy... the ultimate White Magic. Magic that might stand against Meteor. Perhaps our last hope to save the planet from Meteor.<br/>If a soul seeking Holy reaches the planet, it will appear.<br/>Ho Ho Hooo.<br/>Meteor, Weapon, everything will disappear.<br/>Perhaps, even ourselves.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Even us!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>It is up to the planet to decide.<br/>What is best for the planet. What is bad for the planet.<br/>All that is bad will disappear. That is all.<br/>Ho Ho Hooo.<br/>I wonder which we humans are?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Search for Holy... How do we do it?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Speak to the planet.<br/>Get the White Materia... This will bond the Planet to humans.<br/>Then speak to the planet.<br/>If our wish reaches the planet, the White Materia will begin to glow a pale green.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...This is the end.<br/>Aerith had the White Materia...<br/>But when Aerith died, it fell from the altar...<br/>That's why...... this is the end.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Ho Ho Hooo!<br/>Ho Ho Hooo!<br/>Ho Ho Hooo!<br/>Look at this!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Ancient's writing.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Can you read it?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>I can't even make it out!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>This's no time for jokes...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>I'm not an Ancient. I can't read this thing!<br/>I may be old, but my eyes aren't completely bad yet. Look closely below the writing.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>There's something written in chalk......... (even sunlight can't reach)...... (Key)</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>It was probably written by a scientist who's been here... He probably used all his energy to make out these two words.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Key......? To what?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>I don't know... But, it probably has something to do with our riddle.<br/>The riddle... then it must have something to do with Aerith.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>So this note points to where the key is?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Probably...<br/>Use these words as clues and go find the key.<br/>I'll continue to figure out the Ancients' writing.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>A place (Even sunlight won't reach) is where the (key) is, right?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>When you find the key, or when you can't go any further, come back here.<br/>Maybe I'll understand more from the writing and get some new information for you.</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud nods and leaves the city to look for the key.</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="key"></a>Searching in the submarine, they find it in an underwater tunnel near the entrance to Lucrecia's cave.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Do you think it's......?</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>...analysis completed...<br/>...exact date of origin cannot be determined...<br/>...estimated to be several thousand years old...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Key of the Ancients...</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>Received Key Item "Key to Ancients"!</p>
<p class="italic">They return to the City of the Ancients.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Oh! You've found it!<br/>That Music Box over there. We'll put the key in it.<br/>I'll go use the key. You all wait here.<br/>And watch closely what happens.<br/>Ho Ho Hooo!</p>
<p class="italic">He puts the key in the music box, a tune plays, and a waterfall crashes down on the center structure.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Now, go inside. Hope may be inside... Or......</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud goes to look.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>This was just a screen to project an image!<br/>Look! Look at the image projected on the screen of the water!</p>
<p class="italic">They watch as the screen shows the White Materia at Aerith's death. In the water, it is glowing a pale green.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...It's glowing.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Ho Ho Hooo!! It's pale green!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Aerith. Aerith has already prayed for Holy.<br/>...After I gave up the Black Materia to Sephiroth...... Aerith' words came into my dreams...<br/>She said, she was the only one who could stop Sephiroth...... And to do that, there was a secret here...<br/>That was Holy...... That's why, she had the White Materia. Aerith knew about here... and what she had to do.<br/>Aerith has left us great hope. But, it cost her her life... her future...<br/>I'm sorry... Aerith. I should have figured this out sooner.<br/>...You left us without saying a word...... It was all so sudden, so I couldn't think...<br/>That's why it took so long for me to find out... But, Aerith... I understand now.<br/>Aerith... I'll do the rest.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>You mean, WE...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>The hope she left us... We've gotta take a chance with it!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>!? ...you mean WE.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>The big gift the flower girl left for us... it'd be sad if we didn't finish it!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud looks at his companions and nods.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Thank you... Aerith.<br/>Aerith' voice has already reached the Planet. Just look at the glow of the White Materia.<br/>But...... how about Holy? How come Holy isn't moving?<br/>Why?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Something's getting in its way.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>......Him......<br/>He's the only one that could do it.<br/>...Sephiroth. Where are you?</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud turns to go, and his PHS rings.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What the?</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>whisper... whisper... (sorry I was a little surprised).</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What happened?</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>You remember when the Junon Cannon disappeared? Actually, Rufus moved it.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Moved it? That big thing......? Where...? Why?</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Rufus wants to destroy Sephiroth with it.<br/>That cannon operates on Huge Materia. But the Huge Materia has already been used in the Rocket Plan.<br/>So since the cannon's useless right now, he decided to move it.<br/>To a place where Materia... no, where Mako is gathered...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>And, where is that!?</p>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic"><a name="shinra"></a>Cut to Midgar, where the Sister Ray has been moved. At Shinra Headquarters...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>......That's why, Reeve. It's your job to adjust the reactor's output.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reeve</b><br/>I see......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Hah, hah, hah! Don't worry about adjusting it, Reeve.<br/>Once you open it up all the way everything will go full speed!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>Gya hah, hah, hah! The President's sure done it this time!<br/>If we can only defeat Sephiroth, the idea that Meteor will also disappear is based on different objectives!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Please remember, Mr. President...<br/>It was my idea to fire Mako reactor powered shells.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>Will the shells really reach the far northern border?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Ah, hah hah!<br/>Of course!<br/>But Mr. President, please do not call it a Mako cannon.<br/>This new weapon will be called......<br/>The Sister Ray!</p>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic">Back to Cloud, outside Bone Village.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>............?<br/>Wh, what the...!?</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="highwind"></a>Back on the Highwind...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>What's wrong!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Crew Member</b><br/>It's a strange signal!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>From where?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Crew Member</b> (turning towards Cait Sith)<br/>It's coming from this... person (?)</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Wow!<br/>Hey!<br/>That was a surprise, the controls went crazy.<br/>This ain't good...<br/>Weapon came out of the sea and is heading straight for Midgar.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>The new weapon should stop him, right?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>I don't know if it's ready or not...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Hey! What's gonna happen to Marlene!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Doncha worry none, Marlene's in a safe place. She's with Aerith' mama.<br/>Barret!!<br/>What was that scratching just now!?<br/>As long as Marlene is safe, who cares what else happens, right?<br/>I been itchin' to say this to ya fer a while now!<br/>When ya blew the Midgar No. 1 up, how many folks d'ya think died?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>...that was for the life of the planet. Ya gotta expect a few casualties.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>A few? Whaddya mean 'a few'? What may be a few to y'all is everythin' to them who died......<br/>Protect the planet. Hah! Y'all sure sound good!<br/>Ain't no one that'd go against ya. So ya think ya can do whatever y'all want?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>I don't wanna hear that from no one in Shinra...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>......nuthin' I can do 'bout that...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Stop it!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Cait Sith...... Barret, he knows what he did.<br/>What we did in Midgar can't be forgotten no matter what the reason.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">She turns to Barret.</p>
<p class="block-inline">Right? We haven't forgotten, right?</p>
<p class="italic-inline">She turns back to Cait Sith.</p>
<p class="block-inline">I know you.<br/>You can't quit the company because you're worried about the people in Midgar, right?<br/>......Cloud?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>OK! Let's go! We'll beat Weapon ourselves!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>Hey Cloud......<br/>You think we can win against that monster? We got a chance of winnin', right?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>How would I know?<br/>But that's no reason for us to just let him go!<br/>We're goin' to Midgar and fight Weapon! Come on, let's move!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>That damn Weapon... He's one big *&amp;$*&amp;%$...<br/>Even Midgar's gonna be in trouble.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Whether you love it or hate it...<br/>You just can't bring yourself to leave Midgar, can you?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Nanaki</b><br/>Midgar...<br/>I hated the fact I was caught by Hojo and taken back to the lab where they did all kinds of experiments on me...<br/>But because of that I was able to meet you all...<br/>People you meet... others you don't...... strange isn't it?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cait Sith</b><br/>Cloud, you do your best now, hear!?<br/>I know y'all can't forgive the Shinra, but them poor folks in Midgar ain't done a bit wrong!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vincent</b><br/>......we still can't seem to get near Sephiroth...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cid</b><br/>That reminds me, there was a test rocket that landed in the Slums of Midgar long ago.<br/>I remember I was relieved when I heard it never blew up.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Yuffie</b><br/>Are you waiting for Cloud?<br/>He's flying right now, so you can't get him.<br/>Were you going to force me into the submarine right now?<br/>Quit it! If you want to go, then just leave me behind.<br/>............ooooooh. What're you talking about? I......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Bugenhagen</b><br/>Traveling is wonderful, isn't it?......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Learner Pilot (L13)</b><br/>Cloud! I'm going!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Okay<br/>- Excuse me, but could you wait?</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others head for Midgar.</p>


</scene>
