<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><scene name="TheWorldAfterRocket">



<sp>The World - After the Rocket's Failure </sp>

<sp>Kalm </sp>
<sp>Junon </sp>
<sp>Costa del Sol </sp>
<sp>North Corel </sp>
<sp>Gold Saucer </sp>
<sp>Gongaga </sp>

<stage>At Kalm...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Redhead">Redhead</speaker><boxstart/>Listen to me! Something really big's happening in Midgar.<boxstart/>They were just saying on TV it was <referent name="Rufus">Rufus</referent> second strategy and...<boxstart/>That big cannon's pointed due north...... You think the target's...... <referent name="Sephiroth">Sephiroth</referent>? </sp>
<sp><speaker name="Man">Man</speaker><boxstart/>Sephiroth put up a huge barrier around the North Crater.<boxstart/><referent name="Rufus">Rufus</referent> wants to use a mammoth cannon to smash the barrier.<boxstart/>He plans to have Shinra troops rush in and attack <referent name="Sephiroth">Sephiroth</referent> after the barrier falls. </sp>
<stage>Inside the second house...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Old Man">Old Man</speaker><boxstart/>Everyone at Shinra's in an uproar because they heard Weapon's coming.<boxstart/>I heard a big hydroplane carrying secret weapons, got attacked by Weapon and was sunk at sea...... </sp>

<stage>At Lower Junon...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Woman">Woman</speaker><boxstart/>I heard a war's about to start! And that's why they're moving the big cannon! </sp>
<sp><speaker name="Older Man">Older Man</speaker><boxstart/>Listen <referent name="Cloud">Cloud</referent>, I'm over the hill, but Priscilla is still a child.<boxstart/>Isn't there a way to protect at least her from Meteor? </sp>
<stage>In Upper Junon...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Soldier">Soldier</speaker><boxstart/>The Shinra Army's gathered at Midgar. Now it's just a matter of time <referent name="Sephiroth">Sephiroth</referent>'s dead.<boxstart/>What... me? I don't mind. I'll just wait here. My life is important to me. </sp>

<stage>At Costa del Sol...</stage>
<stage>Johnny's House...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Johnny">Johnny</speaker><boxstart/>No, no, NO!! Meteor's getting bigger by the minute!!<boxstart/>I wanna live on the edge right now! I want to build a home with my woman and grow old together!<boxstart/>If you can't do it, I will! And that's that!<boxstart/>I'm gonna do my best, so you hang in there, too! </sp>

<stage>At North Corel...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Man in Hardhat">Man in Hardhat</speaker><boxstart/>Hey, the Gold Saucer reopened!<boxstart/>We've got to play hard to get our minds of Meteor. </sp>
<stage>At the ropeway station...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Redhead">Redhead</speaker><boxstart/>I'm gonna use all my life savings before Meteor hits! </sp>
<sp><speaker name="Blond">Blond</speaker><boxstart/>I know how you feel, but what if Meteor doesn't hit us? What are you gonna do then? </sp>
<sp><speaker name="Station Man">Station Man</speaker><boxstart/>The Gold Saucer reopened. Why don't you go play hard and clear your heads as well as your pockets? </sp>

<stage>At Gold Saucer...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Dio">Dio</speaker><boxstart/>I thought about it, but there was only one conclusion.<boxstart/>I believed that because of the way things are, there's a need for a place like this.<boxstart/>Enjoy yourselves... Ha ha ha ha... </sp>
<stage>By this point, Cloud may be able to access the special duel at the Battle Arena.</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Receptionist">Receptionist</speaker><boxstart/>You know, I've been thinking about it for a while now, but you must be pretty strong?<boxstart/>Probably strong enough to take on the top 1 or 2 fighters?<boxstart/>Maybe you'll be good enough for the big match......<boxstart/>How 'bout it? There's a private battle only for the strongest. Wanna try? </sp>
<sp><speaker name="Cloud">Cloud</speaker><boxstart/>- Let's do it<boxstart/>- Not interested </sp>
<sp><speaker name="Woman Outside Battle Square">Woman Outside Battle Square</speaker><boxstart/>I watched you win eight battles. I want you to have this! </sp>
<sp><speaker name="unspecified"/><boxstart/>Received "Sprint Shoes"! </sp>
<sp><speaker name="Woman Outside Battle Square">Woman Outside Battle Square</speaker><boxstart/>Good luck in the future, too! </sp>

<stage>At Gongaga...</stage>
<sp><speaker name="Old Man">Old Man</speaker><boxstart/>Shinra's tried a lot of things, but it's only HUMAN. It's fate that Meteor will kill the people. </sp>
<sp><speaker name="Redhead">Redhead</speaker><boxstart/>...Everyone's going to die. Everything's coming to an end. </sp>

</scene>