<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<scene name="ShinraBuilding">

<h1>The Shinra Building</h1>

<h4><a href="#arrival">Arrival at Shinra Headquarters</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#60">The 60th Floor</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#61">The 61st Floor: Lounge</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#62">The 62nd Floor: Mayor's Office + Shinra Library</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#63">The 63rd Floor: Coupon Exchange</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#64">The 64th Floor: Gym</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#65">The 65th Floor: Model of Midgar</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#66">The 66th Floor: Conference Hall</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#67">The 67th Floor: Hojo's Lab</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#captive">Captivity</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#blood">A Trail of Blood</a></h4>
<h4><a href="#escape">Escaping the Shinra Building</a></h4>
<hr></hr>
<p class="italic"><a name="arrival"></a>Cloud, Tifa, and Barret stand before Shinra Headquarters.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Hey, you oughta know this building well.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Not really, now that I think about it,<br/>This's the first time I've ever been to the Headquarters.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>I heard about this place before.<br/>Every floor above the 60th is special and not easy to get to even for employees.<br/>Must be where they took Aerith.<br/>The security's pretty light now. Awright, let's go!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Wait a second! You're not thinking of just going right through the main entrance, are you?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Well what else does it look like!? I'm gonna kick some Shinra butt and......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>That's not going to work! We've got to find another way...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Ain't gonna be no other way! If we keep wastin' time like this, Aerith'll...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I know that! But if we get caught here...<br/>Hey, Cloud. ...What should we do?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Let's bust on in!<br/>- Let's sneak in quietly</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Let's bust on in!</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>That's more like it! C'mon, let's go!!</p>
  <p class="italic">They run inside.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Receptionist</b><br/>Excuse me! If you don't have an appointment, you'll just have to...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Don't need no appointment... This is a 'mergency!<br/>Anyone who don't wanna get their face bashed in better git outta the way!!</p>
  <p class="italic">He aims his gun-arm at the receptionist.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Receptionist</b><br/>Yaagghh!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>Who do they think they are?<br/>Y, You don't think that's AVALANCHE?<br/>Intruders! Seize them!!</p>
  <p class="italic">Everyone else flees as the soldiers run to fight Cloud and the others, who defeat them with ease.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Let's go to the top!</p>
  <p class="italic">They run up a staircase to the second floor. There is a bulletin board there with flyers.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Bulletin</b><br/>Shinra, Inc. This week's phrase<br/>Shinra's Future Is The World's Future!!<br/>Mako Energy For A Brighter World!!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Flyer</b><br/>Turtle's Paradise Newsletter No. 2<br/>The end of another hard day. Wouldn't you like to sit back with a tall cool one?<br/>You can at the Turtles Paradise!! Stop in today!<br/>There's nothing like a smooth one after work!</p>
  <p class="italic">There's a shop nearby, and a couple is looking at a car advertisement on a television screen.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Woman</b><br/>Honey...... Buy me that car!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Man</b><br/>But baby, that's way too expensive.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Woman</b><br/>What did you say?</p>
  <p class="italic">They notice Cloud and the others.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Man + Woman</b><br/>.........</p>
  <p class="italic-inline-nopad">They flee.</p>
  <p class="block-inline-nopad">Hh, hey!<br/>Ww, wait for meeeeeeee............!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Shopkeeper</b><br/>Welcome. Today we have on special...<br/>Eagghhh!!<br/>Here, t, take the money...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Don't want no money. AVALANCHE ain't no packa criminals.<br/>We jes want back what your boss stole from us.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Shopkeeper</b><br/>A, AVALANCHE?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Now we ain't gonna hurt you. Might even pay ya, if ya help us.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Shopkeeper</b><br/>Ok... ok... well...<br/>Thank you and come again... Forget I said that...</p>
  <p class="italic">If they try to open the treasure chests...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Shopkeeper</b><br/>You opened up all those things without asking and, hey wait!</p>
  <p class="italic">Cloud and the others leave and get on an elevator.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>......What's wrong?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I didn't want to start a ruckus till we saved Aerith.<br/>I should have known that was impossible though...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Heh, heh, heh.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What is it? You're givin' me the willies.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>So there are times when even you fight for other people. I am impressed.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Who cares if you're impressed...?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Y'know, I ain't so good at sayin' this, but... Sorry... for lotsa things.</p>
  <p class="italic">A red light starts flashing and alarms go off.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Wh, what the!?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Look!</p>
  <p class="italic">The numbers on the elevator are all scrambling.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>DA-MN...!<br/>I don't care where, Cloud! Just stop it!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>What's going on!?</p>
  <p class="italic">The elevator stops four times before finally reaching the 59th floor. On some of the floors, instead of fighting Shinra soldiers, a Shinra employee may attempt to get on the elevator.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Shinra Employee</b><br/>Oh man!!<br/>No, uh, that's all right. My mistake. I'm, uh, not getting on.<br/>Oh man!!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad">[<a href="#59">on to the 59th floor</a>]</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Let's sneak in quietly</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>See? Let's be careful and find a different route!</p>
  <p class="italic">They enter through a side entrance and start climbing the stairs.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Yo! You really gonna take these stairs all the way up?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Well, we've got to get to Aerith to help her somehow.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Talk about out of the way...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I don't have time to argue with you. I'm going!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Y, yo, Tifa! Don't go off by yourself...</p>
  <p class="italic">Barret and Cloud follow Tifa up the stairs.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Don't know... Why... the hell... We gotta... climb...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Because we don't want to start a commotion until we've saved Aerith.<br/>I doubt that's possible though...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>...heh heh heh.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Knock it off. You're giving me the creeps.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>So even you will fight for someone else. I had you figured wrong I guess.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Who cares what you figured!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>I'm just sayin' mebbe I was wrong...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>heh heh heh......</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What's that supposed to mean, Tifa?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>...how much farther do these stairs go on?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Why don't you ask them?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>It's not one of them endless stairways or somethin', d'ya think?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Of course not!!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Right... couldn't be that...<br/>Are we there yet?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Not yet.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>...there yet?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I said not yet!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Yo...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Look, don't even ask! We're way way way way far away from being there yet, ok!?</p>
  <p class="italic">Finally Barret stops, panting.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Damn, man! I've had it! I'm going back!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>And take just as long going down as you did coming up?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>............</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>C'mon, Barret. Pull it together!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Yeah, well all I know is I'm just flesh 'n' blood... 'cept for this arm of mine.<br/>Don't treat me like I'm some ex-member of SOLDIER or somethin'......</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>What about me!? I'm human too! Oh, do what you want, I'm going on!</p>
  <p class="italic-inline-nopad">She turns to continue up the stairs, then stops.</p>
  <p class="block-inline-nopad">......?</p>
  <p class="italic-inline-nopad">She pulls her skirt down.</p>
  <p class="block-inline-nopad">Yaah! Barret! You go first!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>What're ya ignorant? I didn't mean that...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>All right, all right!<br/>Cloud, you go on ahead too!!</p>
  <p class="italic">They continue on...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Yo... What floor is this?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...I gave up counting.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Why they gotta build these buildings so damn tall?<br/>That Shinra... They're just no damn good.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>.........</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>huff... Man, I'm beat...<br/>Marlene, Daddy wanted to see your face one more time...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Would you stop acting like a retard and climb!?<br/>It's just a bit more!<br/>...maybe.</p>
  <p class="italic">They finally reach the top and stop, panting.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>F...finally... M... made it...<br/>N... never wanna see... no more stairs the rest of my life...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>huff... puff... this really takes it out of you...<br/>But this is it. We'd better get ready...!</p>
  <p class="italic">They all walk through the exit to the 59th floor.</p>

<p class="italic"><a name="59"></a>If Cloud tries to go back down...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Hey Cloud!<br/>You come all this way, you thinkin' of goin' back down to the 1st floor?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Yeah<br/>- No......</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Yeah</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>This ain't no time for fooling around!</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">No......</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Yeah, that's right! Let's go on then!</p>

<p class="italic">Some soldiers are standing by the next set of elevators.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Soldiers</b><br/>Destroy the intruders!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others fight off the soldiers, one of whom drops something.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What's this?</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>Received Key Item "Keycard 60"!</p>
<p class="italic">They take the elevator up to the 60th floor.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I hope Aerith is all right.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>This is the real thing. Don't let your guard down.</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="60"></a>The Shinra employee meant to be watching the cameras is asleep on duty, so he doesn't see Cloud as he steps out of the elevator onto the 60th floor. There are a collection of bust statues here with guards on patrol.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Guard</b><br/>What're you doing here!? No unauthorized people are allowed here!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Guard 2</b><br/>People like you don't belong here! Go on, get out!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Lookit that, all them guards is runnin' around.<br/>Cloud, you go on ahead and signal us when it's safe to come.<br/>When those guards turn around, MOVE!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Stay in the shadows!</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p class="italic"><span class="highlight">If Cloud messes up...</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Guard</b><br/>Hey there! What do you think you're doing there!?</p>
  <p class="italic">Cloud and the others fight off the guards.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>What the hell're ya doin'? Come on gotta do it again!</p>
  <p class="italic">If Cloud messes up four times they end up taking out all the guards.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>I shoulda known it'd turn out like this...<br/>If I'd known it'd be like this in the first place...</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Shhh! Now let's move on.</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p class="italic"><span class="highlight">If they make it past the guards successfully...</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Ok! We gonna rock!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Remember, we're here to save Aerith.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Hell, I know that!</p>

<p class="italic"><a name="61"></a>They continue on to the 61st floor, the door to which is stuck open so they can get through without a keycard. It is a lounge area with a huge tree in the center and a number of employees milling around.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Woman</b><br/>I don't remember seeing your face before... You new here?<br/>Say, you're cute. Let me teach you some... things.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Things?<br/>- Um, I'm kinda in a hurry...</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Things?</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Woman</b><br/>Wipe that stupid look off your face. I was only going to teach you how to get to the next floor.<br/>The higher ups in the company use the floors above the 60th floor. But you can't get there without a keycard.<br/>Get a keycard and you can use the elevators freely.</p>
  <p class="italic-inline-nopad">Ding.</p>
  <p class="block-inline-nopad">...voila! You hear that sound and the door opens.<br/>Just remember there are different types of cards. One keycard alone won't let you go everywhere.<br/>For example,<br/>'Keycard 60' only takes you to the 60th floor. 'Keycard 65' only takes you to the 65th floor.<br/>It's a security system worthy of Shinra. After all, all the power in Midgar and the world, for that matter, is controlled by them.<br/>Oh, I have to go. Gotta get back to work!</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Um, I'm kinda in a hurry...</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Woman</b><br/>Oh? That's too bad...</p>

<p class="indent"><b>Man</b><br/>This is the lounge floor. Above us are the special floors for the big wigs in the company.<br/>It's tough working under someone. Tires you out.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man 2</b><br/>What's keeping her? Did she forget her keycard?<br/>Even employees can't walk around above the 60th floor without a keycard.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man 3</b><br/>The hell are you? What're you doin' around here?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Where's Aerith?<br/>- ......</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Where's Aerith?</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Man 3</b><br/>Aerith? How did you know that name? You must be...!?<br/>Aerith, you mean that kid. The receptionist. Yeah, I was startin' to worry 'bout her myself.<br/>And so another rival appears on the scene, eh?<br/>You mean, she's not? It's someone else?</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">......</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Man 3</b><br/>Oh, I see. So you must be that whatcha call it...<br/>Shinra, Inc. Repair Division!!<br/>You know, it looks like this building is starting to fall apart.<br/>This door was just pushed open. You ought to fix this right away.<br/>Oh yeah, and take a look on the other floors too. I'll give you this.</p>
  <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p>Received Key Item "Keycard 62"!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Man 3</b><br/>This door is stuck wide open. Better fix this right away.</p>

<p class="indent"><b>Woman Sitting Down</b><br/>I thought I heard a ruckus downstairs a minute ago. Do you know what that was all about?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man Sitting Down</b><br/>No idea. But no need to worry because everything above the 60th floor is safe.</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="62"></a>Having obtained the next keycard, they continue on to the 62nd floor, which houses several different libraries. They find a man waiting outside someone's office.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hart</b><br/>How do you do?<br/>This is the Midgar Mayor's Office. Mayor Domino is in his office.<br/>I am the Deputy Mayor. If you should have any questions feel free to ask me...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Domino</b><br/>Hmm? Oh, and who might you be?<br/>You all must be those... ahem... Me? I'm Domino, the Mayor of Midgar.<br/>Actually, I'm Mayor in name only. The city and everything in it is really run by Shinra, Inc.<br/>My only real job is watching over Shinra's documents...<br/>Me! The Mayor! A librarian! Ohh......<br/>You want to get upstairs? I tell you what, if you can guess the password, I'll give you my keycard.<br/>Yes, that's it. Guess the password and I'll give you my keycard!<br/>Get it on the first try and I'll even throw in a special item!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hart</b><br/>Did you speak with the Mayor?<br/>What? A password? Oh, I get it...<br/>He's got way too much time on his hands. But you can't really blame him, Everything in Midgar is controlled by President Shinra.<br/>Maybe I can help you.<br/>What do you want to know?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- HELP<br/>- Forget it</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">HELP</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Hart</b><br/>Sure, sure. All right.<br/>As a public servant, it's my job to serve the needs of the people.<br/>So here's a hint...<br/>...for 500 gil.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Give him the money<br/>- Forget it!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Hart</b><br/>Oh, my... well, Thank you very much.<br/>Now listen. On this floor are four research libraries for four different sections of Shinra, Inc. ...<br/>Parts of the password are hidden in each of the libraries.<br/>Pay careful attention to the files in each room.<br/>The name of each library is written on the plaque outside the door.<br/>What can I do for you?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Give me the hint again<br/>- Give me the next hint<br/>- Uh, nothing</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Hart</b><br/>Sure, sure. All right.<br/>As a public servant, it's my job to serve the needs of the people. So here's a hint...<br/>...for 1000 gil.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Give him the money<br/>- Forget it!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Hart</b><br/>Oh, my... well, Thank you very much.<br/>Now, in each library will be one file mixed in from another library.<br/>Look carefully at the numbers on each file.<br/>What can I do for you?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Give me the hint again<br/>- Give me the next hint<br/>- Uh, nothing</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Hart</b><br/>Sure, sure. All right.<br/>As a public servant, it's my job to serve the needs of the people.<br/>So here's a hint...<br/>...for 2000 gil.</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Give him the money<br/>- Forget it!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Hart</b><br/>Oh, my... well, Thank you very much.<br/>There is a number at the beginning of each file name.<br/>Of course there's a number even on the files that don't belong in that library.<br/>Match the number with the letters in the title of the file.<br/>If the file starts with a 4, then check the fourth letter and... well, you get the idea.</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Forget it</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Hart</b><br/>...I see. Then, I guess that's that.<br/>Good luck finding it on your own.<br/>If you still can't find it. I'll just be right over here. Ready to tell you anytime...</p>

<p class="italic">The placement of the books and the numbers vary each time, but below are the titles in their correct libraries without numbers. In each library there is also a television screen displaying a notice.</p>
<p class="indent">[Shinra, Inc. Urban Dev. Research Library]<br/>Reactor construction chart<br/>Problems with Plate construction in Midgar<br/>New plans for Urban Planning<br/>Midgar City map: Sectors 0-4<br/>Midgar City map: Sectors 5-8<br/>An illustrated guide to City Planning</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>Materials are non-circulating!<br/>It is forbidden to remove any materials from this floor.</p>
<p class="indent">[Shinra, Inc. Scientific Research Library]<br/>Biological characteristics of the Ancients<br/>Data on experimental animals living near Midgar<br/>The Jenova Project<br/>The Ancients in History<br/>File on Dr. Gast, Biologist<br/>Final evolutionary stages in land dwelling life</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>This is the Scientific Research Library.<br/>Materials for the...<br/>Urban Dev. Library<br/>Peace/Weapon Dev. Library<br/>Space Dev. Library<br/>are held in their respective libraries...</p>
<p class="indent">[Shinra, Inc. Space Dev. Research Library]<br/>Diminishing Mako energy and Planet movements<br/>Modern history of Midgar space program vol. 1<br/>Modern history of Midgar space program vol. 2<br/>Results of failed space mission "YA-79"<br/>Economic report: Space Dev Program<br/>Shinra rocket space travel</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>This is the Space Dev Research Library.<br/>Click on the plate in front of each library to see what it is.</p>
<p class="indent">[Shinra, Inc. Peace Preservation/Weapon Dev. Research Library]<br/>Special peace keeping law<br/>Materia production and its military uses<br/>Ranks and extended use of Mako weaponry<br/>Heidegger's Shinra peace keeping law<br/>Plan for new land weapons<br/>Economic report: anti-Shinra activities</p>
<div class="highlight"/><p>This is the Public Order/Weapon Development Library.<br/>Return materials where you found them. Do not mix materials from other libraries.</p>
<p class="italic">After obtaining the password, Cloud returns to Domino's office.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Domino</b><br/>Got it?<br/>Then tell me.<br/>So, what's the password?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- BEST<br/>- KING<br/>- ORBS<br/>- BOMB<br/>- MAKO<br/>- HOJO<br/>- Wait a second</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p class="italic-inline-nopad">If Cloud guesses it right the first time, Domino will say any of the following depending on the password. (ORBS and HOJO are never the password.)</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Domino</b><br/>BEST!!<br/>God, I love the sound of that! BEST!! I AM the best... ME!! No matter what anyone else says, you'd better believe it.<br/><br/>KING!!<br/>God, I love the sound of that! KING!! President Shinra sucks! I should be King of Midgar!<br/><br/>BOMB!!<br/>God, I love the sound of that! BOMB!! I'm so angry, I'm like a walking time bomb waiting to explode!<br/><br/>MAKO!!<br/>God, I love the sound of that! MAKO! If I had a lot more of it, I would be a real Mayor!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Domino</b><br/>......hmm. Well, ok. Here, take it.</p>
  <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p>Received "Keycard 65"!</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Domino</b><br/>I never thought you'd get it on the first try...<br/>Just goes to show you can't judge a book by its cover. Oh well, a promise is a promise. Take this, too.</p>
  <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p>Received "Elemental" Materia!</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p class="italic"><span class="highlight">If Cloud guesses wrong...</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Domino</b><br/>Nope! You're ALL wrong! It's a much better word than that! Try again!</p>
  <div class="block"/>
    <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p class="italic-inline-nopad">If Cloud guesses right the second time, Domino goes through one of his WORD!! exclamations, hands over the keycard, and then...</p>
    <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Domino</b><br/>......hmm. Well, ok. Here, take it.<br/>Hmm. It appears you're not completely stupid.<br/>Fine then, take this.</p>
    <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p>Received "Elixir"!</p>
  
  <div class="block"/>
    <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p class="italic-inline-nopad">If Cloud guesses wrong the second time, too, Domino doesn't give him anything extra whenever he finally gets it right.</p>
  

<p class="indent"><b>Domino</b><br/>Why would I do something like this, you ask?<br/>To mess with them, of course! Shinra's been torturing me forever.<br/>That's why I was a little rough on you all just now. Now go up there and really make them suffer.<br/>This ought to make us even! Heh heh heh......<br/>But my card will only get you to the 65th floor.<br/>Can you believe how they treat me? ...ME! Like some common employee...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hart</b><br/>If you run into President Shinra please don't tell him about this.<br/>I can't be a partner to anymore trouble for Shinra.</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="63"></a>Having obtained Domino's keycard, Cloud and the others continue on to the 63rd floor, which is a maze of small storage rooms with locked doors. Near the escalators is a room with a computer.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Computer</b><br/>...bing... bing... Enter command</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- All clear<br/>- Coupon Change</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">All clear</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Computer</b><br/>......bing... bing... Start again from the beginning?<br/>The information and materials you received on this floor will all be cleared.<br/>Clear them?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Yeah......<br/>- No</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Computer</b><br/>...... ......... ......... Cleared.<br/>You are permitted to open any door on this floor up to three times.</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Coupon Change</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Computer</b><br/>...beep......beep...... You do not have any coupons.</p>

<p class="italic">There is an air duct next to the computer.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>An air-duct... It doesn't look like I'll be able to climb in here.</p>
<p class="italic">The ducts can, however, be reached from some of the other rooms. By using the air ducts and the three doors, Cloud can manage to get all three coupons and return to the computer.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Computer</b><br/>...bing... bing... Enter command</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- All clear<br/>- Coupon Change</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">All clear</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Computer</b><br/>......bing... bing... Start again from the beginning?<br/>The information and materials you received on this floor will all be cleared.<br/>Clear them?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Yeah......<br/>- No</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Computer</b><br/>...... ......... ......... Cleared.<br/>You are permitted to open any door on this floor up to three times.</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Coupon Change</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Computer</b><br/>You can exchange your coupons for items. Here are the items you can have...<br/>A coupon.........'Star Pendant'<br/>B coupon.........'Four Slots'<br/>C coupon.........'All' Materia<br/>Please use caution... once you have exchanged coupons for items you may not use 'All Clear' function.<br/>Exchange coupon?</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Yeah......<br/>- Naw</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Computer</b><br/>...... ......... ...... Coupon exchange complete.</p>
  <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p>Received "Star Pendant"!</p>
  <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p>Received "Four Slot"!</p>
  <div class="highlight-nopad"/><p>Received "All Materia"!</p>

<p class="italic"><a name="64"></a>Cloud and the others move on to the 64th floor. Here, they find an exercise room, a nap room, and a locker room.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Receptionist</b><br/>You must be a visitor. Please feel free to use any unused machines.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Woman on Treadmill</b><br/>...huff... puff... If you're tired, you should get some rest in the next room.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man on Treadmill</b><br/>...huff... weeze... I'm starting to worry about my belly......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man Lifting Weights</b><br/>Hmph, hmph... Since I'm head of security for this building, stamina's very important to me.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Vending Machine</b><br/>Take one to restore your energy!! 'Shinra Gym Special Drink'<br/>Only 250 gil!!<br/>- Try it out<br/>- Don't try it</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Try it out</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Nothing...</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Don't try it</span></p>
  <p class="italic">Nothing happens.</p>

<p class="indent"><b>Man in Nap Room</b><br/>...zzz... Please...... let me...... get some... rest......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Sign in Bathroom</b><br/>Out of Order<br/>Please use a different Floor<br/>Shinra Company Repair Management Department</p>
<p class="italic">In the locker room, some of the lockers are unlocked.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What is this...... a Megaphone?<br/>Hanging on to this won't do any good...</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="65"></a>They move on to the 65th floor, where there is a model of Midgar in a central room, and treasure chests placed around in side rooms.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>A model of Midgar... born from Mako sucked right out of the earth.<br/>Parts of the model are missing...<br/>- Place the Midgar parts<br/>- Leave it alone</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Sounds like something opened up...</p>
<p class="italic">Placing all the parts in the model opens up the treasure chest with Keycard 66 in it.</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="66"></a>Cloud and the others move on to the 66th floor, which is dominated by a large conference room. Several offices and a bathroom take up the remaining space.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Secretary</b><br/>Whew, I'm so sick of carrying all these files...<br/>But I get to meet lots of guys. I guess that's the benefit of being a secretary!</p>
<p class="italic">If Cloud speaks to her after she enters one of the offices...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Secretary</b><br/>Hello!! (He's kinda cute. But looks like that girl's with him... But that's kinda exciting!)</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man</b><br/>Is it just me or does the Conference Room smell? There's some sort of stench coming from somewhere...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man 2</b><br/>........................<br/>........................<br/>........................<br/>........................<br/>........................<br/>........................<br/>Phew!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man 3</b><br/>Hey, when you're in the bathroom, do you ever hear whispers coming from somewhere?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man 4</b><br/>They're having another executive meeting. I wonder if it's about that Plate incident.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man 5</b><br/>It gives me the feeling that I AM alive. The feeling of moving this world, just with my hands.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Woman</b><br/>Come on, we're building the future of Mako!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud enters a stall in the bathroom. Above it is a vent.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Flush?<br/>- Climb up?<br/>- Get out of here</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud climbs up and enters the duct system, the others following. He, Barret, and Tifa peer down through the next vent at the conference room below, where Shinra's executives are having a meeting.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Geez--! That's a lotta suits!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reeve</b><br/>We have the damage estimates for Sector 7.<br/>Considering those factories we already set up and all the investments, the damage is estimated at approximately 10 Billion gil...<br/>The estimated cost to rebuild Sector 7 is...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>We're not rebuilding.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reeve</b><br/>What?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>We're leaving Sector 7 as it is.<br/>And restarting the Neo-Midgar plan.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reeve</b><br/>...then the Ancients?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>The Promised Land will soon be ours.<br/>I want you to raise the Mako rates 15% in every area.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Palmer</b><br/>Rate hike! Rate hike! Tra, la, la! And please include our Space Program in the budget!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>Reeve and Scarlet will divide the extra income from the rate increase.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Palmer</b><br/>Oh man!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Reeve</b><br/>Sir. If you raise the rates, the people will lose confidence...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>It'll be all right.<br/>The ignorant citizens won't lose confidence, they'll trust Shinra, Inc. even more.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Heidegger</b><br/>Ha ha ha!<br/>After all, we're the ones who saved Sector 7 from AVALANCHE!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>That dirty #$*$^</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>Hojo. How's the girl?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>As a specimen, she is inferior to her mother. I'm still in the process of comparing her to her mother, Ifalna, but for now the difference is 18%.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>How long will the research take?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>Probably 120 years. It's probably impossible to finish in our lifetime. Or in the lifetime of the specimen too, for that matter.<br/>That's why we're thinking of breeding her. Then we could create one that could withstand our research for a long time.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>What about the Promised Land? Won't it hinder our plans?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>That's why I need to plan. The mother is strong... and yet has her weaknesses.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He starts giggling.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>That concludes our meeting.</p>
<p class="italic">They all get up and head for the door. Scarlet pauses to look up.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Scarlet</b><br/>Something stinks...</p>
<p class="italic-inline">She, too, walks out.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>They were talking about Aerith... right?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>I dunno.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Probably.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Let's follow 'em.</p>
<p class="italic">They climb back out of the ventilation shaft and into the bathroom. Hojo has fallen behind the others in leaving the conference room, and they follow him at a distance. They stop to wait for him to reach the top of the escalator before entering the stairwell after him.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Hojo... huh...?</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="67"></a>They follow Hojo up before the door can lock after him, thereby reaching the 67th floor. Here sprawls the lower floor of Hojo's laboratory. The three pause by the escalator.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>I remember him.<br/>That Hojo guy. He's in charge of the Shinra's Science Department. Cloud, don't you know him?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>This is the first time I've actually ever seen him. So... that's what he looks like...</p>
<p class="italic">They continue on.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man</b><br/>Let's see... The specimen Hojo asked me for is...</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others head down the hall and enter the lab, in the center of which is a glass chamber holding a lion-like creature. Someone is coming, so they hide behind some crates.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man</b><br/>Is this today's specimen?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>Yes. We're starting right away. Raise it to the upper level.</p>
<p class="italic">The man walks away, and Hojo leans forward to touch the glass.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>My precious specimen...</p>
<p class="italic">He turns and leaves. Tifa walks up to the glass.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Precious specimen...?<br/>Is it going to be used for a biological experiment?</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud suddenly takes notice of a chamber to his right, and looks through the window.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Jenova...</p>
<p class="italic">He clutches his head in pain and collapses. Tifa runs over as he gets up.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Jenova... Sephiroth's... So... they've brought it here.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Cloud, be strong!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Did you see it?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>See what?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>It's moving...... still alive?</p>
<p class="italic">Barret looks inside.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Where's its $#&amp;*&amp;@ head? This whole thing's stupid. Let's keep goin'.</p>
<p class="italic">They go upstairs to find Hojo standing before a corresponding glass chamber directly above the other, inside of which is Aerith.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Aerith!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>Aerith? Oh, is that her name? What do you want?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>We're taking Aerith back.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>Outsiders......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Shoulda noticed it earlier, you...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>There's so many frivolous things in this world.</p>
<p class="italic">Barret runs over and aims his gun-arm at Hojo.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>Are you going to kill me? I don't think you should.<br/>The equipment here is extremely delicate. Without me, who could operate it? Hmm?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Ugh.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>That's right. I recommend you think things out logically before you make any rash moves.<br/>Now, bring in the Specimen!</p>
<p class="italic">The elevator within the glass chamber raises, bringing the lion-creature up to join Aerith. It starts growling at her and she runs away to pound on the glass.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Cloud, help!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What do you think you're doin'?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>Lending a helping hand to an endangered species... Both of them are on the brink of extinction...<br/>If I don't help, all these animals will disappear.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...animal? That's terrible! Aerith is a human being!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>You're gonna pay!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Barret! Can't you do anything?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Awright!! Step back!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>Stop!!</p>
<p class="italic">Barret fires at the glass chamber, and it starts glowing brightly. Hojo moves closer to the door.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>Wh... what are you do-- Oh! My precious specimens...</p>
<p class="italic">The door opens and the lion-creature jumps out, pouncing on Hojo.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Now's our chance to get Aerith!</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He runs inside the chamber.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Thanks, Cloud.</p>
<p class="italic">She runs out. Cloud starts to follow, but stops and turns around.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Cloud... what's wrong?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...The elevator is moving.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Hojo</b><br/>This is no ordinary specimen. This is a very ferocious specimen!</p>
<p class="italic">The lion creature looks up from attacking Hojo to address them.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red</b><br/>He's rather strong. I'll help you all out.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>It talked!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red</b><br/>I'll talk as much as you want later, Miss.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>We'll take care of that monster.<br/>Somebody take Aerith somewhere safe...<br/>- Tifa, I'm countin' on you!<br/>- Barret, take care of her!</p>
<p class="italic">Aerith runs out with either Tifa or Barret.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What's your name?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red</b><br/>Hojo has named me, Red XIII. A name with no meaning whatsoever to me. Call me whatever you wish.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Come on!</p>
<p class="italic">They dispatch Hojo's specimen, and Aerith rejoins the group.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Aerith, you all right?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>She seems all right, ...in many ways.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>I have a right to choose, too. I don't like two-legged things.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>What are you?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>An informed question. But difficult to answer. I am what you see.<br/>...You must have many questions, but first, let's get out of here. I'll lead the way.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Cloud... so you did come for me.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>I apologize for what happened back there. I was merely acting to throw Hojo off guard......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Now we've saved Aerith, ain't no need to be in this buildin'! So let's get the hell outta here!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>If all five of us go together, we'll be noticed. Let's break up into two groups.</p>
<p class="italic">Whoever he doesn't choose to come with him says goodbye:</p>
<blockquote class="party">
	<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Later! Meet up at the 66th Floor Elevator!</p>
	<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Aerith</b><br/>I'll see you later!! We'll be waiting at the 66th Floor Elevator.</p>
	<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>We'll be going first! Meet at the 66th Floor Elevator.</p>
	<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>Don't be late. Do you know where the Elevator is? The 66th Floor!</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="italic">The other group leaves.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Man</b><br/>No! Please don't kill me. I only did what Hojo told me to do.<br/>To prove it to you... here, this is the key card to the 68th Floor. Would I be doing this if I was the enemy?<br/><div class="highlight"/><p>Received Key Item "Keycard 68"!</p></p>
<p class="italic">The man then flees.</p>
<p class="italic">If Cloud attempts to go anywhere but the elevator...</p>
<blockquote class="party">
	<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>Where you goin'? Everyone's waitin' at the 66th Floor Elevator.</p>
	<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Not that way! Everyone's on the 66th Floor Elevator.</p>
	<p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Where are you going? Everyone's waiting for us at the 66th Floor Elevator.</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="italic">Cloud and the others get on the 66th floor elevator. Rude of the Turks enters behind them.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>H, hey! What is it?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rude</b><br/>Would you press 'Up' please?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Turks? Must be a trap...</p>
<p class="italic">Rude steps aside and Tseng enters.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tseng</b><br/>It must have been a real thrill for you... Did you enjoy it?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Ggh...</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="captive"></a>The Turks take them up to the 70th floor, where they find the others also taken captive. Aerith is missing, though.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>You all got caught, too?<br/>Where is Aerith!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>In a safe place.<br/>She's the last surviving Ancient...<br/>Don't you know? They called themselves the Cetra, and lived thousands of years ago. Now they are just a forgotten page in history.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>Cetra... That girl, is she a survivor of the Cetra?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>Cetra, or the Ancients will show us the way to the 'Promised Land.' I'm expecting a lot out of her.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>The Promised Land? Isn't that just a legend?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>Even so, it's just too appealing to not to pursue.<br/>It's been said the Promised Land is very fertile.<br/>...If the land is fertile...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Then there's gotta be Mako!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>Exactly. That is why our money sucking Mako Reactor is necessary.<br/>The abundant Mako will just come out on its own.<br/>That is where Neo-Midgar will be built. Shinra's new glory...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>@$#*^%! Quit dreamin'!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>Oh really, don't you know? These days all it takes for your dreams to come true is money and power.<br/>Well, that is all for our meeting.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rude</b><br/>Come on! Outta his way!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud, Tifa, and Red XIII turn away without protest, but Barret hangs back.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Hold it! I got a lot I wanna say to you!</p>
<p class="italic">He starts towards President Shinra, but Rude drags him away.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>President Shinra</b><br/>If you need something else... talk to my secretary.</p>
<p class="italic">The scene changes to the detainment area, where they've been placed in cells. Cloud with Tifa, Barret with Red XIII, and Aerith by herself.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Psst (Can we get out?)</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- (Leave it to me)<br/>- (Kinda hard)</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">(Leave it to me)</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Psst (Cloud, you're so brave!)</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">(Kinda hard)</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Psst (Don't give up!)</p>

<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I wonder how Barret is doing</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Hey!<br/>Aerith is an Ancient and the real name of the Ancients is Cetra.<br/>The Ancients know where the Promised Land is and the Shinra is searching for that Promised Land.<br/>I only heard stories 'bout the Promised Land. I don't know if it really exists.<br/>Is that right?<br/>The Shinra believe that the Promised Land is full of Mako energy.<br/>Which means, if the Shinra get there, they'll suck up all the Mako energy.<br/>...and the land'll wither away. The Planet's gonna get weaker.<br/>I can't just leave 'em be. I'm recruitin' new members!!<br/>Me, Tifa, Cloud... and Aerith too.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He turns to Red XIII.</p>
<p class="block-inline">How 'bout you?</p>
<p class="italic">Red XIII turns away and lies down.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>You're so damn boring.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I wonder how Red XIII is doing</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>............Grandpa.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Grandpa!? Ha, ha, ha...... Grandpa, hmm...... ha, ha, ha......</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>What's so funny?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Nothin'...... ha, ha</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I wonder how Aerith is doing</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Cloud, are you there?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Aerith!? You safe?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Yeah, I'm all right.<br/>I knew that Cloud would come for me.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Hey, I'm your bodyguard, right?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>The deal was for one date, right?</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa sits up from where she's been lying on the cot.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>............oh, I get it.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>...!? Tifa! Tifa, you're there too!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>EXCUSE me.<br/>You know, Aerith. I have a question.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>What?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Does the Promised Land really exist?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>...I don't know.<br/>All I know is...<br/>The Cetra were born from the Planet, speak with the Planet, and unlock the Planet.<br/>And...... then...<br/>The Cetra will return to the Promised Land. A land that promises supreme happiness.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...What does that mean?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>More than words...... I don't know.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Speak with the Planet?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Just what does the Planet say?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>It's full of people and noisy. That's why I can't make out what they are saying.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>You hear it now?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>I, I only heard it at the Church in the Slums. Mother said that Midgar was no longer safe. That is... my real mother.<br/>Someday I'll get out of Midgar... Speak with the Planet and find my Promised Land.<br/>...That's what mom said.<br/>I thought I would stop hearing her voice as I grew up, but...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Let's just get some sleep</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="blood"></a>They settle down to rest. Cloud wakes before the others, finding the door to his and Tifa's cell open.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>The door's open... When did it open?</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He runs out into the hall to find the guard dead.</p>
<p class="block-inline">What's happened?</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He runs back into the cell.</p>
<p class="block-inline">Tifa... Wake up!</p>
<p class="italic">She sits up immediately.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>What's wrong?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Something's wrong. Look outside.</p>
<p class="italic">Tifa runs out, and Cloud joins her.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I wonder what happened...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>He should have the key on him...<br/>Come on, Tifa, get Aerith. I'll go help Barret and the others.</p>
<p class="italic-inline">Cloud runs into Barret and Red XIII's cell.</p>
<p class="block-inline">Barret, Red XIII... come with me. Something's wrong.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>How'd you get in? Why's the door open!?</p>
<p class="italic">Barret and Red XIII run out.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>This's kinda eerie...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Must've been attacked by...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>The hell's goin' on'!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>No human could've done this.<br/>I'll go on ahead.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>I'll clean up back here, so you guys go ahead. And don't get caught by Shinra!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Come on, let's follow Red XIII!</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud, Aerith, and Tifa follow Red XIII to where the Jenova specimen was kept, finding a huge bloody hole in the front of the empty chamber, with a trail of blood across the floor.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>Jenova Specimen... Looks like it went to the upper floor using that elevator for the specimens.</p>
<p class="italic">Red XIII heads for the elevator and the others follow.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>It looks like it leads up...</p>
<p class="italic">They follow the trail of blood to the 70th floor, where they find President Shinra dead at his desk, impaled by the Masamune blade.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>He's dead... The leader of Shinra, Inc. is dead...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Then this sword must be...!?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Sephiroth's!!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...Sephiroth is alive?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Looks like it. Only Sephiroth can use that sword.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Who cares who did it!? This is the end of the Shinra now!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Palmer</b><br/>Uh!</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He comes out from behind a pillar and tries to run, but Cloud and Barret catch him.</p>
<p class="block-inline">P, p, p, please, don't kill me!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>What happened?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Palmer</b><br/>Se... Sephiroth. Sephiroth came.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Did you see him? Did you see Sephiroth?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Palmer</b><br/>Yeah, I saw him! I saw him with my own eyes!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>You really saw him?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Palmer</b><br/>Uh! Would I lie to you at a time like this!? And I heard his voice too!<br/>Um, he was saying something about not letting us have the Promised Land.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Then what?<br/>Does that mean that the Promised Land really exists and that Sephiroth's here to save it from Shinra?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>So he's a good guy then?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Save the Promised Land? A good guy? No way!!<br/>It's not that simple! I know him! Sephiroth's mission is different!</p>
<p class="italic">Palmer frees himself and runs off as a helicopter arrives outside.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Rufus! &amp;*%$! I forgot about him!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Who's that?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Vice President Rufus. The President's son.<br/>I heard that he's been assigned somewhere else for a long time...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>I've heard that no one's ever seen him bleed or cry.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>I only know his name.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I wonder what kinda person he is...</p>
<p class="italic">They run outside to where Rufus and Palmer are, Palmer apparently just finishing up a quick report.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>So... So Sephiroth was actually here. ...By the way.<br/>Who are you guys?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I'm Cloud, former SOLDIER First Class!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>I'm from AVALANCHE!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Same here!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>...a flower girl from the slums.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b> (growling)<br/>...a research specimen.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>What a crew.<br/>Well, I'm Rufus. The President of Shinra, Inc.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>You only President, 'cause yer old man died!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>That's right. I'll let you hear my new appointment speech.<br/>...Old man tried to control the world with money. It seems to have been working.<br/>The population thought that Shinra would protect them.<br/>Work at Shinra, get your pay. If a terrorist attacks, the Shinra army will help you.<br/>It looks perfect on the outside.<br/>But, I do things differently.<br/>I'll control the world with fear. It takes too much to do it like my old man.<br/>A little fear will control the minds of the common people. There's no reason to waste money on them.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>He likes to make speeches just like his father.</p>
<p class="italic"><a name="escape"></a>Cloud turns to Barret.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Get outta this building with Aerith!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>What?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I'll explain later! Barret! This is the real crisis for the Planet!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>The hell's that supposed to mean?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I'll tell you later! Just take my word for it now! I'll go after I take care of him!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Awright, Cloud!</p>
<p class="italic">Barret and the others run back downstairs. Aerith hangs back.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Cloud... I just thought of something.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...I'll wait for Cloud! Everyone, get to the elevator!</p>
<p class="italic">Aerith nods, and she, Red XIII, and Barret run on.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Hmm, it's going to get pretty ugly from here on. We should check on our equipment.</p>
<p class="italic">They get on the elevator, and a combat robot attacks them from the other car. They defeat the robot and continue down.</p>
<p class="italic">Back to Cloud, as he and Rufus face off...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>Why do you want to fight me?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>You seek the Promised Land and Sephiroth.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>Hm, exactly.<br/>Mm? Did you know that Sephiroth is an Ancient?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...A lot has happened. Anyway, I can't let either you or Sephiroth have the Promised Land!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>I see. I guess this means we won't become friends.</p>
<p class="italic">Cloud fights Rufus and his pet Dark Nation, until Rufus decides to beat a dignified retreat.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Rufus</b><br/>Heh... That's all for today.</p>
<p class="italic">Rufus grabs hold of the helicopter and it flies off with him. Cloud runs downstairs to where Tifa is waiting.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Where's Rufus?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>I couldn't finish 'em. Looks like this's gonna get complicated.</p>
<p class="italic">Back to Aerith and the others as they arrive on the first floor and head for the exit.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>I'll go on ahead!</p>
<p class="italic-inline">He runs out, firing his gun-arm, but soon comes back in.</p>
<p class="block-inline">*&amp;^%(*... surrounded, huh?<br/>If I was alone this wouldn't be a thang but, I gotta reputation to protect.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>You all get out while you can.<br/>It's not you they're after... it's me.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Yeah, well that ain't happenin'.<br/>You got caught up in this over Marlene. Now, it's my turn to watch out for you!<br/>Ok, playtime's over for you jackasses...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>...thank you, Mr. Barret!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Who you callin' Mr. Barret? That don't sound right!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>Well then...<br/>If you are through talking, may I suggest that we think of a way to get out of here.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Huh? Oh, oh yeah... You a cold man. Just like someone else 'round here I know.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>Did you say something?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Notta thing. So what're we gonna do?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Barret!!</p>
<p class="italic-inline">Tifa comes running down from upstairs.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Tifa! Where's Cloud?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>Everyone, over here!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Huh? What's up? Where's Cloud?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I'll tell you later! Hurry, Hurry!!</p>
<p class="italic">They all climb into the display truck and drive it out the window, following Cloud on the motorcycle. Shinra troops follow on motorcycles, but Cloud dispatches them with his sword. They reach the end of the road, and a large, armored tank/robot attacks from behind. They defeat the robot, and find themselves standing at the edge of Midgar.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Well, what do we do now?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Sephiroth is alive. I... I have to settle the score.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>And that'll save the Planet?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>...Seems like it.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>Awright, I'm going!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>I'll go too. ...I have things that I want to find out.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>About the Ancients?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>......Many things.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>I guess this's good bye, Midgar.</p>
<p class="italic">They climb down a cable to the ground level.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Red XIII</b><br/>I'm going back to my hometown. I'll go with you as far as that.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...I guess this is the start of our journey...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- You hate traveling?<br/>- It's dangerous. You sure you want to go?</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">You hate traveling?</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...I don't know. But, I don't have anywhere else to go. So I guess it doesn't really matter whether I like to travel or not.</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">It's dangerous. You sure you want to go?</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>......Mmm. But you know, it should be all right if you keep your promise.</p>

<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>You know what? This is the first time I've ever left Midgar...</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Really? ...You worried?<br/>- It's dangerous. You sure you want to go?</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Really? ...You worried?</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Aerith</b><br/>A little, ...no, maybe a lot. But I have my bodyguard, right?</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">It's dangerous. You sure you want to go?</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Aerith</b><br/>I thought you'd say that!</p>

<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>We told Aerith's mom to go somewhere safe, so Marlene should be safe too.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>- Yeah, she should be<br/>- Hmm, I don't know</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Yeah, she should be</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Aerith</b><br/>She said she didn't want to stay in Midgar anymore. ...Maybe it's for the best.</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p><span class="highlight">Hmm, I don't know</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Aerith</b><br/>Stop it, Cloud! I'm worried too.</p>

<p class="indent"><b>Cloud</b><br/>Then...<br/>- Let's stay here for a while<br/>- Let's go!</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>We need a group leader for our journey. 'Course only me could be the leader.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Tifa</b><br/>You think so...?</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Aerith</b><br/>It would have to be Cloud.</p>
<p class="indent"><b>Barret</b><br/>^#$^%...... awright. Go Northeast to a town called Kalm. If something happens, we'll meet up there.<br/>'Sides, we can't have 5 people strolling down the fields. It's too dangerous. Split us into 2 parties...</p>
<div class="block"/>
  <p class="italic"><span class="highlight">If Cloud chooses Aerith + Tifa for his party...</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Barret</b><br/>...Thought you'd do that.<br/>Later, at Kalm!</p>

<div class="block"/>
  <p class="italic"><span class="highlight">If Cloud chooses Barret + Red XIII for his party...</span></p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Aerith</b><br/>...Unexpected</p>
  <p class="indent-nopad"><b>Tifa</b><br/>...combination.<br/>Well, have fun with just the guys.<br/>We'll see you at Kalm!</p>

</scene>
